Guide to Joan Roelofs Collection on the Green Movement TAM.651
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Joan Roelofs Collection on the Green Movement
1970-1995
TAM.651
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
1.0 linear feet in 1 record carton
Joan Roelofs was Professor of Political Science at Keene State College from 1979 until 2012 specializing in green public adminsitration, the political power of foundations and the ideas of pre-Marxist socialist Charles Fourier. She is the author of Greening Cities: Building Just, Sustainable Communities, and Foundations and Public Policy. She is also a practitioner of book arts. This collection consists of various papers, articles, notes and fliers regarding the enviornment, labor issues and the socio-political situation in America during the late-20th century; as well as issues of numerous publications examining contemporary issues in climate change, environmental politics, and energy policy and development.
Roelof, Joan
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Historical/Biographical Note
Joan Roelofs was Professor of Political Science at Keene State College from 1979 until 2012 specializing in green public adminsitration, the political power of foundations and the ideas of pre-Marxist socialist Charles Fourier. She is the author of Greening Cities: Building Just, Sustainable Communities, and Foundations and Public Policy. She is also a practitioner of book arts.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
There is no documentation to indicate who donated this collection or when. The accession number associated with this gift is 2014.149.
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists of various papers, articles, notes and flyers regarding the enviornment, labor issues and the socio-political situation in America during the late-20th century; as well as issues of numerous publications examining contemporary issues in climate change, environmental politics, and energy policy and development. The collection includes multiple issues of Green Politics and Synthesis/Regeneration.
Environmental education.; Environmental justice.; Environmentalism |z United States.; Environmentalists |z United States.; Green movement |z United States.
- Regeneration, circa 1985-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Regional, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- National, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
- Green International, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Green Archives, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Social Ecology Network (Labor and the Enviornment), circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Vox Monadock, Fall 1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Gateway Greens, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Green Consensus, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Jersey Greens Journal, Fall 1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Green Gathering Materials, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Groundworks on Nuclear Waste, circa 1990 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Issues of Green Politics, circa 1990 (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
- Issues of Synthesis/Regeneration, circa 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 16-20)